mshinstitute.org 2009-01-16

# Privacy Policy — Mount St. Helens Institute

**Privacy Policy**  
At the Mount St. Helens Institute, we value your support and are committed to protecting your privacy. Our site is a safe environment for anyone who signs up for membership, to volunteer, to make a donation, or to participate in a Mount St. Helens Institute activity.  

 **Information we collect and how we use it.**  
We collect personal information from you only when it is specifically and knowingly provided by you. When you make a donation online, we ask for your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. When you sign up to volunteer or receive our email newsletters we collect names, email addresses, and topics of interest if indicated.  When you sign up to climb Mount St. Helens or to participate in a field seminar this is done through a contracted third party.  The contractor asks for your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and credit card information.    

**Links to Third Party Sites**  
Mount St. Helens Institute partners and contracts with third-party service providers to host our web site and other online services.  Third-party service providers are not permitted to use or share any personally identifiable information that we provide to them.  Mount St. Helens Institute does not share any of the personally identifiable information we collect with other outside parties, unless we have received your permission to do so.    

It is our policy not to sell, trade, or rent your personal information to anyone without your advance permission. We will not share your personal information with any third party, except to contracted service providers acting on our behalf or unless ordered to do so by a court of law. We reserve the right to change our policy at any time. If we choose to change our policy, you will be given the option to remove your name from our database.   

**Child Privacy**  
We do not knowingly solicit or collect personally identifiable information online from children under the age of 13. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information online, we will take all reasonable measures to delete such information from our databases and to not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others or as required by law).

 **Use of Personal Information**  
Employees of the Mount St. Helens Institute, or contracted service providers acting on our behalf, will have access to your personal information only to conduct appropriate business. We will use your information to process your transaction and to verify credit card data. We will use your mailing address to send emails with requested information and information about the Mount St. Helens Institute and its activities. It is our policy to discontinue contacting any person upon that person's oral or written request directed to us, our fundraising agents, or other official representatives. All subscriber emails sent will have a simple unsubscribe option, as required by law.

 **Use of Non-Personal Information**  
We also collect various kinds of basic, non-personal information. This includes total number of visitors, pages viewed, referring websites, and other non-identifying statistics that contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information. We use this aggregate information to pursue partnerships that further our mission, improve the quality of our website, and to make your experience on our website as smooth as possible.

 **Protecting Your Information**  
If you supply us with your credit card information to make a donation, we will encrypt the card number.  You may also send donations to our address provided below.

 **How to Contact Us**  
If you would like to terminate receipt of information from the Mount St. Helens Institute, or change information previously provided, please contact us via e-mail, regular mail or telephone (all information provided below).

 **Questions**  
If you have any questions regarding this policy, please contact us via e-mail, regular mail, or telephone (all information provided below).

Mount St. Helens Institute  
42218 Yale Bridge Road  
Amboy, WA  98601  
Phone: (360) 449-7883  
Email: info@mshinstitute.org
